Uh, I think we'll slowly get started.
Can Can you hear me? Just uh maybe
somebody send a thumb up or something
like that if you can hear me. Okay, just
so I know I'm not talking into uh into
nothing. Seems like I am I'm going
through. So, uh I'll get started. My
name is Alexander and I'll be running
this office hours call with me. I have
Sebastian. Uh so, we're we're kind of
small team uh today uh due to vacations
and such. So yeah, later on in the
session we'll open up for Q&As's but uh
yeah, if we can't answer all your
questions, just uh feel free to post
them in our ILGO repository.
Yeah. So the agenda for today is I'll
start talking about what's new and then
I'll get into one announcement and then
we'll get into the Q&A.
Uh so to get started with what's new in
ALGO for GitHub, I actually want to
start by talking about what's not new.
uh because this stuff uh was something
that we presented last time uh in last
hour last month's office hours. Uh the
difference now is that we've shipped it
as part of version 7.2. Last month it
was only in preview. Uh so yeah, we have
a couple new features in the latest
version. Uh make sure to upgrade uh and
so you can take advantage of these
things. I won't go through uh the
features here, but if you go to ILGO
release notes, you can you can read more
about them.
Now to what's actually new. Um we have
these three features that we want to
show today. Uh they're all in preview.
Uh so yeah, not available in 7.2. Uh but
they will be available in 7.3 when we
release that.
Um so the first one is a starter
dashboard for ILGO telemetry. Uh this
was based on some feedback that we got
uh some office hours ago earlier in the
year that algo has the capability of
emitting telemetry but it would be nice
if we could have you know some custories
or some beginner dashboard that you can
kind of get started with so you can you
know get get started with telemetry
it'll go telemetry quickly. Uh and so we
made a a small dashboard for that. It's
pretty much like a plug-and-play Azure
Azure data explorer uh report. So, what
you have to do is go to the ILGO
repository and download a JSON file
there and then you have to fill in a
couple of things. Um, and then as soon
as you upload it to data explorer, it
will just connect to your uh application
insights and you'll get uh you'll get
some basic like reporting capabilities.
Uh, I'm sorry. I think the screenshots
here are a little bit uh grainy, but uh
yeah, essentially it'll give you the
ability to see what workflows you have
running, which ones are failing. Um, you
can see and uh a breakdown of which how
many how many minutes is AO running on
GitHub hosted runners or self-hosted
runners. Uh this might be useful for
people that you know run on self-hosted
runners and want to make sure that
absolutely everything is on self-hosted
runners and so on. Um
you can see uh which algo versions
you're running on in your different
repos and when was the last time you
updated
and you can see deprecations. So every
now and again in ALGO we we'll deprecate
certain settings and we'll we'll warn
you by basically emitting to telemetry
some warnings. It'll you can also see
them in the the warnings uh on on the
GitHub page. But uh but we also emitted
to telemetry. So this will give you like
a central place where you can see all
the the kind of warnings that you have
for your repos or if you're using
settings that are deprecated.
Uh so hopefully you know you become
aware of these things before before
they're actually deprecated and and
something might break uh in your repo.
The next one is uh is a rather big one
uh custom template repositories. This
this basically gives you the capability
of adding your own template repository
that you can spawn other repositories
out of similar to how algo PTE or ALGO
app source uh works today. Uh now you
get the capability of adding your own
template repository uh where you can add
your own custom scripts or custom
workflows and so on and those will be
synced when you run update elgo system
files those things would be synced to
your other elgo repositories. Uh so I
made like a small
uh graphical representation of it. So
today what happens is you have my repo
one and my repo 2 and when you update
when you run update a go system files
the those repos will look in in this
case algo pt could also be a go app
source uh for updates to the workflows
uh with custom templates you can
basically stick your own template
repository in the middle.
So when you run update ago system files
in your own template repository, you you
grab the latest changes from elgo pd
um and then you can set your my repo one
and my repo 2 to look at your at the my
template repository instead of the elgo
pte repository so that you basically get
the latest changes from elgo pte plus
whatever customizations that you've made
in your my template repo.
Like I said, this could give you a give
you a central place to kind of uh
distribute your if you have a your own
workflow that you made or a script or
something, you can put that in my
template and then when you run update
system files, they'll be propagated to
my repo one and my repo 2.
Um on a similar note around
customizations, we also added the
ability to add custom jobs. Uh so this
this gives you the ability to basically
edit the YAML files that ALGO ships with
out of the box um but only to a limited
extent. So you can add your own custom
jobs to these workflows as long as you
you prefix it with custom job dash and
then whatever name you have. Uh so in
this case could be if you want to add to
your CI/CD pipeline a job that creates a
build tag. uh you can now do that in the
in the CI/CD YAML file that we ship as
part of ALGO.
Uh but it does come with a warning which
is you need to be you need to be careful
doing this because we we don't really
make any we can't really make any
promises that we won't change the name
of one of our jobs or something like
that. So you may run into issues if you
start doing this. So just use it very
carefully and please please make sure to
review whenever you run update ecosystem
files because yeah we may make changes
to our YAML files that will break some
of your customizations that you build on
top of it.
Uh so yeah if you're going to use custom
jobs just please be please be careful.
So those were the three features um from
this month. They're all in preview, like
I said, so you won't be able to find
them in version 7.2.
Um, so yeah, if you want to use them
now, you can upgrade to preview.
Before we get into Q&A, just one
announcement that I also did last month,
and that is if you are running an ALGO
version lower than 5.0, then please
upgrade because this will break very
soon. Um, version 5.0 was released more
than a year ago. So, as long as you've
run updated ecosystem files in the last
year, you're probably not on version
5.0.
So, with that said, um we'll get into
the Q&A.
Uh like I mentioned, we're we are small
team today. So, hopefully we can answer
all your questions, but if not, then uh
please post your questions in our in our
repository as well. We're also available
there uh to answer questions or
take bug reports or whatever there might
be.
So basically any questions sorry any
questions today please post them in the
Q&A pane not the chat window.
Yes thank you.
Yes, basically for the remainder of this
office hours call, the next 40 minutes
or so, we'll be available for questions
unless there are no questions and then
we can just cut it short. But yeah,
we'll be available in case
in case you have questions.
feel free to let us know as well if if
there's a certain feature or something
you're missing you're really missing in
Ago then by all means you know let us
know as well this is a good forum for
that too as well as of course the ILG go
repository but now that we're here at
the office hours if there's any features
or comments or anything we're also happy
to take that.
Yeah. So, if there are no questions, I
will give it a couple more minutes, but
if there are no questions, then I don't
see any reason to extend office hours
much longer. We'll I'll stick around
maybe for another I don't know, four or
five minutes or something. If nothing
comes up then uh yeah you can always
reach us on the algo repository either
through creating a GitHub issue or a
discussion depending on what what the
topic of of your request is.
It's also a very small office hours
today. It looks like probably because of
vacations.
doesn't look like there are any
questions. Uh
yeah, so I think we'll slowly start
wrapping up. Just one note, uh next
month it's July and uh we won't have an
office hours call in July. So, uh, next
office hours office hours call will be,
I guess, at the end of August. Last
the last Tuesday of August or something.
It'll be a little while until we have
another one. But again, you can always
reach us on the AGO repository.
So, yes, if there are no questions, then
I think we can just uh just wrap up.
Thank you very much for attending
and we'll see you at the next office
hours.